http://www.amana.com/resources/privacy-notice.html#interest-based-ads

Skip to main content
By closing this message, you consent to our cookies on this device in accordance with our Privacy Notice unless you have disabled them.
Privacy Notice - United States and Canada
Privacy Notice to our customers in the United States and Canada
Effective Date: December 4, 2020
Whirlpool Corporation, Whirlpool Canada LP, and their brands, which include Whirlpool®,
Maytag®, KitchenAid®, Jenn-Air®, Amana®,
Gladiator®, Roper®, Estate®, EveryDrop®, Swash®,
Inglis®, Affresh®, and Speed Queen™ (Canada only) (together
“Whirlpool”, “we” or “us”), values your trust. This Privacy Notice describes how Whirlpool will collect,
use, and share Personal Information (defined below) in locations where this notice is posted, including
on websites and apps (each, a “Website” or “App”), as well as our smart appliances that connect to the
Internet through the Apps using Whirlpool’s cloud-based services (“Smart Appliances”). By using a
Website, App, or Smart Appliance (each, a “Service”), you acknowledge the collection, use, and
disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Notice. Some of our other services or
offerings may be governed by their own privacy notices, which we share with you through those services
or offerings. This Privacy Notice is not a contract and does not create any legal rights or obligations.
Please note that Yummly®, part of the Whirlpool family of brands, maintains a separate
privacy notice, available to Yummly users at www.yummly.com/privacy. If you are a California resident, see
the section “California Residents: Your California Privacy Rights” for information provided
pursuant to the California Consumer Privacy Act.
Summary of Key Provisions:
INFORMATION WE COLLECT:
We collect information you provide to us directly and also collect information about your activities
when you use our Services. We may also receive information about you from other parties. For example,
we may collect your contact information, payment and billing information, Whirlpool account
information, preferences, purchase history, location, and product and ownership information. We may
also collect your IP address, Smart Appliance ID, the type of browser and operating system you use,
your navigation through our Services, and other information about your use of our Services. We may
also collect images, audio, and video you submit or allow the Smart Appliances or Apps to capture. We,
our vendors, and other parties may use cookies and other tracking technologies to recognize you when
you visit our Websites.
DATA SHARING:
We may share your Personal Information with our affiliates, our service providers, our business and
marketing partners, to comply with laws, to protect ourselves or enforce our rights, in connection
with a business transfer, or in other situations where we provide you with notice. Cookies and
tracking technologies are used on our Services, which allows us, advertising networks, social media
companies, and others to place or display ads relevant to you on our Services, as well as on other
websites, apps, services, or devices you may use. We may also share your Personal Information with
companies that market or provide products and services for our brands (such as, for example, service
plans and warranties), unless you opt out from our marketing communications or, in Canada or where
otherwise required by law, unless you have consented. Otherwise, we will not share Personal
Information with unaffiliated parties for their direct marketing purposes unless you have consented.
INTEREST-BASED ADVERTISING:
We use cookies and other technologies to recognize you on unaffiliated party websites so that we can
display targeted ads and other content that is tailored to your interests. We adhere to the DAA’s
Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising as managed by the Digital Advertising
Alliance (DAA). You can opt-out of interest-based advertising by visiting http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ (U.S. residents) or
https://youradchoices.ca/en/tools (Canadian
residents). Our Websites may also allow you to manage certain cookie preferences.
YOUR RIGHTS:
You may opt-out of receiving marketing messages from us by contacting our Privacy Office or by using
the unsubscribe link in our emails. You may correct your information or delete your account using the
account settings on this Website or App, or (if not available) by emailing our Privacy Office us using
the Contact Information below.
If you are a California resident, you have the right to request access to certain information we
collected about you, request deletion of your Personal Information (subject to certain exceptions),
and request to opt-out of the “sale” (as defined under California law) of your Personal Information.
DATA SECURITY:
We take reasonable steps to protect your information, but please be aware that no transmission of
information over the Internet is 100% secure.
SERVICES FROM OTHER PARTIES:
Our Services may contain links to websites or apps owned by other companies. We recommend that you
carefully review their privacy notices.
USE BY CHILDREN:
Our Services are not directed to children under the age of 18.
UPDATES TO THIS PRIVACY NOTICE:
Please review the “Effective Date” at the top of this page to determine when this Notice was last
revised.
Contact us:
You may contact us by email at whirlpool_privacy@whirlpool.com, or by mail at Chief Privacy Officer,
Whirlpool Corporation, 2000 N. M-63, MD 2533, Benton Harbor, MI 49022 U.S.A. You may also contact us
using the toll free number or web form available on the Contact Us page of our websites.
Expand All Collapse AllPrint
I. INFORMATION WE COLLECT
We collect two types of information: Personal Information and Other
Information. “Personal Information” is information that can be used to identify or is reasonably
linkable to you as an individual, and may include Usage Information (defined below). “Other
Information” is information that is not reasonably linkable to an identifiable individual, including
information that has been de-identified or aggregated.
PERSONAL INFORMATION
1. Information you provide directly to us
You may provide your Personal Information in a variety of situations, including when you sign up
for a Whirlpool account, contact us, sign up to receive communications from us, purchase a product
or service, submit your product registration, submit a customer service request, enter a sweepstakes
or contest entry, provide us feedback or survey responses, or otherwise use any of the Services.
Personal Information you provide may include:
Contact information, such as your name, email address, mailing address, social media
information, phone number, etc.
Billing and payment information, such as your credit card number and billing address
Whirlpool account information, including your user name, account number, and password
Product and ownership information and purchase history
Preferences, such as product wish lists, order history, and marketing preferences
Feedback about our products and services
Other information that you choose to share with us
We also may give you the option of submitting Personal Information, such as email address, of other
individuals so we can send them invitations to use the Services (for example, to let them connect to
your Smart Appliance).
Our Apps and Smart Appliances may collect images, video, audio, or other content. For example, a
Smart Appliance might capture images of your food to recognize and automatically cook it, you might
submit photos of suspected product issues so that we can help you resolve them, or you might tell us
what cooking or laundry task you are performing so we can offer you customized tips. We might also
collect information from you to help us improve our products and services.
2. Usage Information
Whirlpool, our business partners, and our service providers may use technologies that collect
information about how you interact with our Services, emails, advertising, and content ("Usage
Information"). Usage Information may include: (i) your device ID and IP address, which is a unique
set of numbers assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider (ISP); (ii) the type of
browser and operating system you use; (iii) your Smart Appliance ID, serial and part numbers, and
the IP address of your home router when you connect a Smart Appliance to our network; (iv) the
physical location of your device or Smart Appliance (as determined, for example, using satellite,
cell phone tower, and WiFi signals); and (v) other information about your online session, such as
the URL you came from to get to our Websites and the date and time you visited our Websites or used
our Apps.
After you connect your Smart Appliance to our network, we may automatically collect information
from the Smart Appliance on a periodic basis, including status (such as whether the Smart Appliance
is off or on, and details about the cycle or function it is performing), instructions that have been
entered on the Smart Appliance, and aspects of its environment that may affect how it operates (such
as input voltage, signal strength, and air temperature). We may track and collect App usage data,
such as the date and time the App accesses our servers, what information has been downloaded to the
App, and the instructions that are transmitted to the Smart Appliance.
The technologies used to collect Usage Information include but are not limited to:
Cookies. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for
record-keeping purposes. We use cookies to improve your experience on our Websites, such as to allow
you to return to the Website more easily, hold your shopping cart, or save your language
preferences. Our service providers and business partners may also use cookies and other tracking
technologies to collect information from visitors to our Websites.
We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies:
A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. We use session cookies to make it
easier for you to navigate our Websites.
A persistent cookie remains on your device for an extended period of time. We set a persistent
cookie to store your account settings so we can identify you the next time you visit or enable
some functions on our Websites. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the
interests of our users to enhance the experience on our Websites.
California residents can learn more about how to manage cookie preferences by clicking on the Do
Not Sell My Personal Information link that may be in the footer of those websites. Your
Internet browser may also provide you with the ability to delete cookies. If you limit or reject
cookies, your ability to use our Websites may be limited.
Web Beacons. Web beacons (also known as “clear GIFs” or “tracking pixels”) are tiny
electronic image files that can be embedded within a web page or included in an e-mail message, and
are usually invisible to the human eye. When used in our web pages, web beacons may tell us such
things as: how many people are visiting our Websites, whether they are one-time or repeat visitors,
which pages they viewed and for how long, how well certain online advertising campaigns are
converting, and other similar usage data. When used in our e-mail communications, web beacons can
tell us information such as the time an e-mail was opened, if and how many times it was forwarded,
and what links users click within the e-mail. Based on this information, we can adjust the content,
products, services, and promotions we provide you to better meet your interests, and make you aware
of Whirlpool products, services, and offers in which you may be interested.
3. Information Provided From Other Parties.
We may receive Personal Information about you from our vendors and other third-party sources,
including commercially-available sources, social media platforms, and providers of third-party
products or services, and combine this Personal Information with other Personal Information that we
have collected. We may also receive information from other- parties’ products or services that you
connect to the Services. For example, if you connect your Smart Appliance to another party’s smart
home service, that party’s service might transmit data to your Smart Appliances, Apps, or us.
OTHER INFORMATION
We may de-identify or aggregate Personal Information and Usage Information to create Other
Information. We use Other Information for a variety of purposes, including to understand our
customers and improve our products and services.
II. HOW WE USE INFORMATION
Personal Information. We use Personal Information to
provide, support, and improve our products and services, to operate, maintain, and improve the
Services, for troubleshooting and maintenance (including for warranty purposes), to better understand
how our products and Services are used, to communicate with you about your account or appliance
(including for product service and warranty issues), to conduct surveys, to administer and evaluate
your eligibility for offers and promotions, for research and development, to verify requests made
pursuant to this Privacy Notice, for security purposes, and, if necessary, prohibit or restrict access
to our Services. We also use Personal Information to send you marketing communications and offer you
products, services, and customized offers from our various brands and from selected other parties. For
example, we may send you a notification when your Smart Appliance needs to be replenished with a
refill or replacement item and may direct you to a third-party business partner from which you can
purchase that item. We may also provide you with customized offers, such as warranties or accessories,
based on your use of the Services. We may also use your Personal Information to better understand what
products and services interest you.
We may also use your Personal Information in other ways we notify you about at the time we collect
your Personal Information. In Canada or where otherwise required by law, we will obtain your consent
for marketing activities.
Other Information. We may use Other Information for any purpose, unless prohibited by law.
Where Other Information is combined with Personal Information, we will treat this combined
information as Personal Information as long as it stays combined.
III. DATA SHARING
We may share Other Information with other parties for any purpose,
unless prohibited by law. We may also share your Personal Information in the following circumstances:
With Our Affiliates. We may share your Personal Information with Whirlpool’s family of
affiliated companies and brands.
With Our Service Providers and Vendors. We may share your Personal Information with our
service providers and vendors to allow them to provide services (such as data analysis,
marketing, surveys, data hosting, information technology, payment or loan processing, customer
support, service plan or warranty services, advertising services, email delivery, and auditing).
With Business and Advertising Partners. We may share your Personal Information with
companies that market or provide products and services for our brands (such as, for example,
service plans and warranties), unless you opt out from our marketing communications or, in
Canada or where otherwise required by law, unless you have consented. Additionally, with your
consent, we may share your Personal Information with other parties to allow them to send you
marketing communications about their own products and services. Cookies and tracking
technologies may be used on our Services, which allows us and advertising networks, social media
companies, and other providers to place or display ads relevant to you on our Services, as well
as on other websites, apps, services, and devices you may use.
Public Posts. When you post comments or content (such as reviews or recipes) on message
boards, blogs, or other interactive features in connection with our Services, your name, city,
state, and additional information may be viewable by others. Be careful when deciding to make
any of your Personal Information available through the Services. If you use any social media
features offered through the Services, such as a Like button, share button, or other features,
these features may collect your information, such as your IP address or which page you are
visiting, and may set cookies to enable the features. Your interactions with these features are
governed by the privacy policies of the social media platforms.
With Other Users of the Smart Appliance. If you choose to allow others to connect to
your Smart Appliance or accept an invitation to connect to another user’s Smart Appliance, the
Smart Appliance’s other users may be able to view information related to your usage. If you sell
or give away the Smart Appliance, we may share Other Information related to that smart appliance
with the new owner (for example, total number of cycles that the Smart Appliance has run).
Legal Disclosure. We may use or disclose Personal Information or Other Information as we
believe necessary: (1) if we determine a policy violation has occurred, to enforce our rights,
or to enforce our Terms of Use; (2) if we believe such disclosure is necessary to identify,
contact, or bring legal action regarding the rights and property of Whirlpool or its affiliates;
(3) to enforce our rights or protect against unauthorized access to our systems or other
inappropriate use of our Services, products, or other services; (4) to comply with laws,
regulations, court orders and subpoenas or similar requests for information by authorities; (5)
to protect your safety and the safety of others; and (6) to assist us in fraud prevention or
investigation.
Business Transfer. We may disclose Personal Information or Other Information in
connection with a reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other
disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets, or stock (including in connection
with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).
IV. INTEREST-BASED ADVERTISING
Select parties may place advertisements for our products and
services on websites operated by others. These parties may use cookies and web beacons to measure the
effectiveness of our ads and to determine the content and advertising to offer you based on your
interests. To support these activities, Whirlpool, our service providers, and business partners may
use information about your visits to our and other websites. We comply with the Self-Regulatory
Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising as managed by the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA). If
you would prefer not to receive interest-based advertising, you can opt-out of this activity at the
DAA website at http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ (U.S.
residents) or Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada (DAAC) website at https://youradchoices.ca/en/tools ( Canadian
residents). You can configure your mobile device privacy or advertising settings via “limit ad
tracking” on an iOS device or “opt out of interest-based ads” on an Android device to limit how apps
track activity for advertising purposes.
California residents can learn more about how to manage cookie preferences by clicking on the Do
Not Sell My Personal Information link that may be in the footer of those websites.
Your browser may offer you a "Do Not Track" option, which allows you to signal your preferences to
certain website operators that you do not want them to track certain of your online activities.
However, our websites do not support Do Not Track requests at this time
Please note that even if you choose to remove your information or opt-out, you will still see
advertisements while browsing online. However, the advertisements may be less relevant to you and
your interests.
V. YOUR RIGHTS
Your Right to Opt-Out. You may inform us that you do not
want Whirlpool to use your Personal Information to provide you with offers or send you newsletters,
emails or other marketing communications, by sending your request using the information in the Contact
Us section of this Notice (below). You may also unsubscribe from receiving promotional communications
from a Whirlpool brand by clicking on the unsubscribe link provided in that brand’s promotional
emails. However, please note that you cannot opt-out from all communications, as Whirlpool and its
brands may need to send you information related to our products (for example, warranties or service
reminders), your orders, or your accounts.
You may also use the contact information below to withdraw your
previous consent to share your Personal Information with other parties (other than our service
providers), or to request removal of your Personal Information from our message boards, blogs, or
other interactive features on our Websites. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal
Information, in which case we will let you know why.
Your Ability to Review/Correct. ou may review, correct, or update your Personal Information
by contacting us, or if you are a registered user, through your account settings. After your account
is deleted/terminated, your information may not be deleted in its entirety from our systems. We may
retain backup copies of your information, including to assist with any legal obligations, resolve
disputes, and enforce our agreements. We will retain your information for as long as necessary to
fulfill the purposes of processing described in this Notice. Keep in mind that we may have multiple
accounts for you, and updating or deleting one account may not update or delete all of them — for
example, your website account may differ from your App account.
Your Smart Appliances Choices. You may choose to receive notifications about your Smart
Appliance (such as notification of cycle completion) through our Apps, which may include
notifications through text message or email. You may select which notifications you would like to
receive, or disable notifications, by changing your settings
You can delete your Smart Appliance from within your App at any time, or delete your App account at
any time within your App. When you take either of these steps, your Smart Appliance will stop
transmitting data to Whirlpool. To confirm that your Smart Appliance is not transmitting data to
Whirlpool, double check that your Smart Appliance is disconnected from your router (such as by
resetting your Smart Appliance's network settings or having your appliance "Forget" your home
network). This will prevent you from being able to use the connected features of your Smart
Appliance. If you disconnect your Smart Appliance from our network, we will continue to handle and
protect any information we have previously received in accordance with this Privacy Notice.
California Residents: Your California Privacy Rights. If you are a California resident,
California’s Shine the Light law permits you to request and receive information about disclosure of
certain of your Personal Information to other parties for their direct marketing purposes. As
described above, we may share your Personal Information with companies that market or provide
products and services for our brands (such as, for example, service plans and warranties), unless
you opt out from our marketing communications or, in Canada or where otherwise required by law,
unless you have consented. To opt-out, contact us using the information in the “Contact Us” section
of this Privacy Notice. Otherwise, it is our policy not to share Personal Information with
unaffiliated parties for their direct marketing purposes (as defined in California’s Shine the Light
law) without your consent. Please note that our brands are part of Whirlpool and are not
unaffiliated parties for purposes of this Privacy Notice.
California residents also have the right to make the following requests. We will not discriminate
against you because you exercise any of these rights
Access – You can request that we disclose to you the categories of Personal Information
we collected about you, the categories of sources from which we collected the Personal
Information, the categories of Personal Information we sold or disclosed, our business or
commercial purpose for collecting and selling your Personal Information, the categories of third
parties with whom we shared your Personal Information, and the specific pieces of Personal
Information we collected about you over the past 12 months.
Deletion – You can request that we delete your Personal Information that we maintain
about you, subject to certain exceptions.
Opt-out – You can request to opt-out of the sale of your Personal Information by either
clicking the Do Not Sell My Personal Information link that may be in the footer of our websites,
or contacting us using the information provided in the Contact Us section, below. For purposes
of this Privacy Notice, “sell” means the transfer of your personal information to a third party
for monetary or other valuable consideration, subject to certain exceptions set forth in
applicable California law. Whirlpool Corporation and Yummly — part of the Whirlpool Corporation
family of brands and a Whirlpool Corporation subsidiary — are a common business for purposes of
the California Consumer Privacy Act. Your opt-out of cookie-based tracking for advertising
purposes is specific to the device, website, and browser you are using, and is deleted whenever
you clear your browser’s cache. Your opt-out of mobile app tracking is specific to the device
you are using.
California residents can make an access or deletion request by contacting us using the information
in the “Contact Us” section of this Privacy Notice (below), by calling toll-free, or by using the
web form available in the Contact Us section on our websites.
We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity prior to responding to your requests. The
verification steps may vary depending on the sensitivity of the Personal Information and whether you
have an account with us. If you designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf,
please ensure the authorized agent identifies him/herself as an authorized agent.
We may deny certain requests, or fulfill a request only in part, based on our legal rights and obligations. For example, we may retain Personal Information as permitted by law, such as for tax or other record keeping purposes, to maintain an active account, and to process transactions and facilitate customer requests. Except as otherwise provided by applicable California law, for purposes of these requests under this section of the Privacy Notice, Personal Information does not include information about job applicants, employees and other of our personnel; information about employees and other representatives of third-party entities we may interact with; or information we have collected as a service provider to our clients.
We may collect California residents’ Personal Information, like contact information, in connection with a financial incentive, such as a discount, special pricing or other promotional offer.
Our offers and incentives generally reflect the value of the relationships that we have with the individuals who participate in these programs.
Participation in these programs is voluntary and you may withdraw at any time by electing not to participate or contacting us using the information in the “Contact Us” section of this Privacy Notice.
We also want our California residents to know the following regarding our data collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information in the past twelve months:
We collect and use the following categories of Personal Information for the business and commercial purposes described in this Privacy Notice: Identifiers; contact and payment information; characteristics of protected classifications under California or federal law (such as demographic information like age and gender); commercial information; internet or other electronic network activity information; geolocation data; audio, electronic or visual information; and inferences
We collect and use these categories of Personal Information for the business and commercial purposes described in Section II of this Privacy Notice.
We collect these categories of Personal Information from the sources described in Section I above, including from you and your devices; our business partners and service providers; our affiliates and subsidiaries; commercially-available sources; social media platforms; providers of third-party products or services.
We disclose each of these categories of Personal Information for our business and commercial purposes as described in this Privacy Notice to the categories of parties described in Section III of this Privacy Notice.
Certain companies place tracking technologies on our sites, allowing them to receive information about your activity on our sites that is associated with your browser or device.
Under California law, sharing data for online advertising may be considered a “sale” of information.
As such, we may “sell” the following categories of Personal Information based on our use of cookies and other tracking tools: Identifiers; commercial information; Internet or other electronic network activity; geolocation data; and inferences.
VI. DATA SECURITY
We are committed to maintaining the security of the data you provide to us.
We use reasonable organizational, technical, and administrative measures designed to protect Personal Information that we store.
We also seek to use third-party service providers capable of protecting the information they maintain or process for us.
Unfortunately, no data transmission over the internet or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.
If you have any security concerns (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us using the information in the “Contact Us” section below.
VII. SERVICES FROM OTHER PARTIES
Our Services may contain links to websites owned by other companies.
Because Whirlpool has no control over the privacy practices or content of these linked sites, we recommend that you carefully review the privacy notice of each website you visit.
This Privacy Notice does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy or other practices of any other parties.
VIII. USE BY CHILDREN
Our Services are not directed to individuals under the age of 18.
We do not seek or knowingly collect information from individuals under the age of 18, and we request that such individuals do not provide Personal Information through our Services.
IX. UPDATES TO THIS PRIVACY NOTICE
We may occasionally update this Privacy Notice.
Please review the “Effective Date” at the top of this page to see when this Privacy Notice was last revised.
If we make any material changes we will notify you as required by law, which may include by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective.
We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
Your use of the Service(s) following these changes means that you acknowledge the revised Privacy Notice.
X. CONTACT US
If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice, please contact us by email at whirlpool_privacy@whirlpool.com, or please write to us at the following address:
Chief Privacy Officer
Whirlpool Corporation
2000 N. M-63
MD 2533
Benton Harbor, MI 49022
U.S.A.
We try to respond to general privacy inquiries within 30 days or as otherwise required by law.
Requests to opt-out from our marketing will be processed within 10 business days.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.
Item added to the compare list, you can find it at the end of this page
Comparing 0 Items
COMPARE
Remove All
